hi everyone today we have a product
comparison review of the jc iksun t420d
and the small jc ixun t3a
we are comparing these two products
against each other and show you which
one might be better for you
a big thanks to jc for sponsoring this
video
let's begin with the jc xixon t420d
let's open up the box
as you can see everything is neatly
packed with enough foam for shipping
the box is built up out of three layers
at the first layer we have a total of
six soldering tips for the soldering
pins there are three different soldering
pins included with this soldering
station
a little more on that later
at the top here we have a total of six
tips for the soldering station
and three more tips in the middle which
we will show you in a bit
along with the power cable one soldering
pin a ground cable and two arms to put
the soldering pins in
at the bottom box there's two more
soldering patterns
when we dive one level deeper into the
box we will find the soldering holders
on the left and right of the box
the right holder has tip cleaner and the
left holder has a sponge
the soldering pad holder has a hinge to
adjust the angle to where it points
[Music]
next up we have the soldering station
itself it's very well packed at the
bottom of the box
at both sides of the soldering station
you will find rails to slide the holders
in
we will also be showing you how to put
the soldering station and its
accessories together let's grab one of
these soldering holders and put it on
the right side of the soldering station
we're starting with the one on the right
you can slide it in from the front to
the back
do the same for the left holder
it's very easy to slide them into place
next we have the two arms which we can
screw onto the sides of the holders
they're not required neither are both of
the holders you should always set up
what works best for you
these are in place we are connecting the
ground wire and both of the holder's
connectors to the back of the soldering
station
now we can grab a soldering pin and
remove the velcro around it the
connector for the soldering pen is at
the back of the holder we can pick any c
245 soldering tip we want and push it
into the soldering pen let's put that
into the holder for now we'll also
connect an additional soldering pen to
the left holder
each soldering pen uses their own size
of soldering tips so make sure to check
you are using the correct size for the
right soldering pen
here we have all the soldering pens to
show you the difference
we can put the c245 soldering tips in
the tip holder at the top of the pen
holders
however this is something we cannot do
with the smallest c115 soldering tips
that also come along with the soldering
station
you can use the soldering tip switcher
to change the soldering tips quickly
[Music]
now we can remove the screen's plastic
and power the solar station up to take a
closer look at the inner works
we'll give you a quick rundown of the
menu we can open it up by clicking the
middle button
the language is conveniently placed as
the first option in the menu
we can turn off the sound feedback the
soldering station gives us under the
sound settings
configure your time settings under the
time tab
under the restore section in the
settings menu you can quickly restore
all the different settings of the device
if you ever mess something up you can
just go back to this window
next we have the temperature tab in the
main menu this is where you can
configure the temperature unit used in
the soldering station under the level
option you can set up the different
channels preset temperatures the
compensate setting becomes interesting
once you have to recalibrate your
station we will do a separate video on
this in the future at the bottom of the
main menu we have dormancy option here
we can configure the dormant temperature
of the soldering station the default
value is 90 degrees celsius the default
delay for when the soldering station
goes dormant is 10 seconds the display
option is a strange one we recommend
keeping it on close and not change it to
open like we did now we have the graph
option which shows you a graph of the
temperature on the left and the power on
the right when we take the pen out you
can see the temperature shoots up very
quickly
okay that was it for the t420d
now it's time to take a look at the
compact jc ixun t3a when we open the box
we're greeted with a white box and a box
that contains the station
let's put the white box aside for now
and start with the soldering station
itself
[Music]
there is a proof of purchase card in
there along with a manual
these were also included in the t420d
the station feels very solid for its
size and looks very stylish
[Music]
the white box that fills up the other 50
of the main box contains all the
accessories for the t3a
a soldering pen a power cable three
soldering tips and a ground cable
there's also an additional box together
with the main box
this box contains the soldering pen
holder
let's grab the soldering station and the
as you can see there's no way to attach
this holder to the soldering station
you'll just have to let it stand on its
own
let's attach the holder cable to the
soldering station and grab the soldering
pen
this one goes into the front of the
station
now we can grab a soldering tip and push
it into the soldering pen
now that we've gone over the contents of
the box we can power up the t3a
if you want to switch the language of
the d3a you can click the set button
then go to the second menu option and
click the turning button
click it again to change the language
and use the channel button to go back in
the menu let's go over all the menu
options really quick
the maximum temperature is set to 500
degrees celsius by default
we recommend a max temperature of 400
degrees celsius to get a longer lifespan
out of your soldering tip
however for these smaller soldering tips
included with the t420d we don't
recommend going higher than 350 degrees
celsius
the lock temp option locks the
temperature so you can't accidentally
change it the dormancy settings are
pretty much the same to that of the
t420d
the sound allows you to turn off the
feedback of the buttons
at the temp level option you can
configure the channel levels of
temperatures
okay now that we have shown you both of
the stations we're going to do the side
by side comparison let's start with some
points we really liked about the jc ixan
t420d
despite only having two holders jc
included three different soldering pens
of different sizes this is a really nice
detail for nano soldering when we say
nano soldering we mean laying down
jumper wires and resistors also each
holder has their own tip switcher this
means that left-sided people can also
use this feature while attaching a
holder not all soldering stations on the
market have this switching the channels
on the t420d is definitely a lot easier
than on the t3a having three separate
buttons is really convenient
the jct 420d is ready for soldering
within two seconds which means it heats
up extremely fast
you can use both soldering pins at the
same time this means it is possible to
have one soldering station for two
people
the menu is really easy to operate using
the navigation buttons as it's their
only function
of course with every positive there's
also some important points that mustn't
be overlooked the smaller c 115 solar
tips are too small to put in the holders
this is pretty annoying if you quickly
want to swap the soldering tip of your
nano soldering pen
there's three soldering pins but there's
only two connectors on the back of the
soldering station it's therefore not
possible to have all three of them
connected at the same time we're looking
forward to see what jc can do with these
things in the future
next we'll go over all the points we
liked about the jc ixun t3a it's really
compact and holds a lot of power for its
size heating up the soldering pin in
only a few seconds the menu has a lot of
options for the size of the station we
were happy to see that the holder has
the same switcher functionality as the
t420d holders
also for this one we have some points
that shouldn't be overlooked there is
only a big soldering pen included in the
box without a nano soldering pen it
makes laying jumpers and soldering
resistors very hard to do
you also can't use the holder for a nano
soldering pen even if you bought one
separately because it simply doesn't fit
ok so now that we have made a quick
comparison going over each point let's
find out which one is the right one for
you if you're soldering all day long and
laying jumpers without much issue or if
you are ready for the next step in your
micro soldering career then the jc ixon
t400 t420d
is the soldering station for you
if you're getting started with micro
soldering the jc ixon te3a is definitely
for you don't let the small size of this
soldering station fool you it has a ton
of functionality which is visible in the
menu
that was it for this review again a huge
thanks to jc for sponsoring this video
and sending us these two soldering
stations we hope you enjoyed if you did
please leave a like and subscribe to our
channel for more that was it for today
till next time
[Music]
you